<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on Shayan Anique</title><link>https://shayananique.com/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on Shayan Anique</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 01:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shayananique.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lets start Windows 8 Development</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-09-09-lets-start-windows-8-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-09-09-lets-start-windows-8-development/</guid><description>So, I am digging in to Windows 8 Development since the last //BUILD Conference, Yup! That’s true I am hacking around Windows 8 story since the first Developer Preview version come out, Now I am running Windows 8 Pro (RTM) on my All machines because I am in love with it. Currently, I am porting my Matchem Poker game and Sound Recorder application for Windows Phone to Windows 8. I am using a smart program called “MonoGame”.</description><content>&lt;p>So, I am digging in to Windows 8 Development since the last //BUILD Conference, Yup! That’s true I am hacking around Windows 8 story since the first Developer Preview version come out, Now I am running Windows 8 Pro (RTM) on my All machines because I am in love with it. Currently, I am porting my &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Matchem Poker&lt;/a> game and &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/6dbd2538-0df6-4231-8ae9-62ea18108c8c">Sound Recorder&lt;/a> application for Windows Phone to Windows 8. I am using a smart program called “MonoGame”. It is a program which you can use to port your XNA Windows Phone Game to Windows 8 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Metro&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will post my full porting story to my Blog Soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Basics&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8devgear">&lt;strong>Download Windows 8 RTM and Visual Studio 2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – in this scenario, you will download an install Windows 8 on your machine (or a VM), and run it as your operating system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/32Launch">30 To Launch&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> – Your App.  Your Idea.  In 30 Days.  Microsoft has set up an amazing program for aspiring app developers to not only keep their app motivation going, but also to help you make your app &lt;strong>awesome&lt;/strong>.  Design consultations, tech reviews, and expert help in Microsoft App Excellence Labs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Resources to Learn From&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8samples">&lt;strong>Windows 8 Code Samples&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – a huge array of Windows 8 sample code for almost everything you can think to do in a Win8 app.  Most of the samples include code using C#, Javascript, C++, or Visual Basic.  &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8sampledownload">You can also download the entire set here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8RCdevcamp">&lt;strong>Windows 8 Dev Camp in a Box&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – a huge pile of presentations, sample code, and hands-on labs for you to use as you start learning about Windows 8 development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cool Stuff to Checkout&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylefont-size-smallwindows-8-productivity-who-moved-my-cheese-oh-there-it-isspanhttpwwwhanselmancomblogwindows8productivitywhomovedmycheeseohthereitisaspx">&lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/Windows8ProductivityWhoMovedMyCheeseOhThereItIs.aspx">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Windows 8 productivity: Who moved my cheese? Oh, there it is.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylefont-size-smalla-hrefhttpcompositecodecom20120816html-css-javascript-and-metro-app-building-on-windows-8-part-1html-css-javascript-and-metro-app-building-on-windows-8-part-1aspan">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Metro App Building on Windows 8 Part 1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Getting Started with Windows 8 Development?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Silverlight Technology in Web Application Development</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-04-22-silverlight-technology-in-web-application-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 14:48:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-04-22-silverlight-technology-in-web-application-development/</guid><description>Microsoft Silverlight is the realization of the .NET Framework supported by various browsers and platforms and intended for .Net software developers to create and present multimedia and RIA applications of the new generation in the Internet. Silverlightcombines the possibilities of the server, the Internet and the personal computer; the possibilities of the control code and dynamic languages, declarative and traditional programming as well as powerful tools of Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF).</description><content>&lt;p>Microsoft &lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong> is the realization of the .NET Framework supported by various browsers and platforms and intended for &lt;a href="http://www.netsoftwaredevelopment.com/">.Net software developers&lt;/a> to create and present multimedia and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rich_Internet_application">RIA applications&lt;/a> of the new generation in the Internet. &lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong>combines the possibilities of the server, the Internet and the personal computer; the possibilities of the control code and dynamic languages, declarative and traditional programming as well as powerful tools of Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong>allows .Net software developers to create ultramodern applications that include the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong>technology is supported by various browsers and platforms such as Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Apple Safari and Google Chrome as well Microsoft Windows OS and Apple Mac OS X.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong>download and installation will take a few seconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong>performs video and audio streaming and provides opportunities for scaling the video quality: from mobile device and PC browsers to video modes 720p for high definition television.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong>also has stylish graphics that can be managed by users — drag, rotate and scale — directly in the browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong> counts data and updates the displayed content but doesn’t interrupt the user’s work while updating the whole page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Applications developed with &lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong> can be launched in web browsers or can be adjusted so as users can launch them on their PCs, outside the browser.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_application_development">Web application developers&lt;/a> and graphics designers can develop &lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong> applications in many ways.&lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong> can be used for developing multimedia and graphics and for working separately using dynamic languages and the control code. &lt;strong>Silverlight&lt;/strong> also allows using the high professional tools such as Visual Studio for writing the code and Microsoft Expression Blend for creating models and graphical design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sources –&amp;gt; &lt;a href="http://www.oxagile.com/article/183-silverlight-technology-web-application-development">Oxagile&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>TCP-based sockets on Windows Phone with support for large amounts of data</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-03-25-tcp-based-sockets-on-windows-phone-with-support-for-large-amounts-of-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 21:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-03-25-tcp-based-sockets-on-windows-phone-with-support-for-large-amounts-of-data/</guid><description>Network communication through sockets is a welcome addition to the Windows Phone platform. Personally, I enjoy using those because of the tremendous performance gain compared to WCF services. One topic, however, seems to be rarely covered when it comes to TCP-based communication between the server (presumably running on a desktop machine) and the client (Windows Phone) = transmission of large amounts of data.
A lot of existing samples assume that the communication, although bi-directional, is done with small data units.</description><content>&lt;p>Network communication through sockets is a welcome addition to the Windows Phone platform. Personally, I enjoy using those because of the tremendous performance gain compared to WCF services. One topic, however, seems to be rarely covered when it comes to TCP-based communication between the server (presumably running on a desktop machine) and the client (Windows Phone) = transmission of large amounts of data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of existing samples assume that the communication, although bi-directional, is done with small data units. For example, &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/5w7b7x5f.aspx">here is a pretty good sample&lt;/a> that I used to build the asynchronous server. The reading callback looks like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>It works perfectly fine on the desktop machine. I am also adding a terminator verification statement that allows me to check whether the whole data set was received:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Although seemingly simple, the data receiving process on a Windows Phone is handled in a different manner. There is no direct implementation of&lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.net.sockets.socket.beginreceive.aspx">Socket.BeginReceive&lt;/a>. Instead, developers work with &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.net.sockets.socket.receiveasync(v=vs.95).aspx">Socket.ReceiveAsync&lt;/a>. Many samples give you this piece of code:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Notice the problem with this snippet. Once the string is received, that will be it. The inbound data length will be limited to the size of the buffer, and the maximum chunk size. The buffer size cannot always be fixed, and it is safe to assume that the developer does not want to allocate too much space for that in one iteration. The default socket chuck size cannot always be accommodated either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resolution comes in a continuous invocation of &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.net.sockets.socket.receiveasync(v=vs.95).aspx">Socket.ReceiveAsync&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Here is where the terminator character plays a major role. Look at** &lt;em>if (dataFromServer.EndsWith(terminator)) –&lt;/em>** that is the flag that shows whether more data is coming or not. With a receiving structure like I showed above, it is possible to keep receiving data until the connection is closed (happens all the time) or the terminator character is detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE:&lt;/strong> If you are wondering what terminator character to use, try going with non-standard ones. For example, &lt;em>&lt;strong>\u00BE&lt;/strong>.&lt;/em> Otherwise, chances are that the actual “terminator” is not the terminating character.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item><item><title>I Just Downloaded Visual Studio 11 Beta To Give It a Try</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-03-11-just-downloaded-visual-studio-11-beta-to-give-it-a-try/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-03-11-just-downloaded-visual-studio-11-beta-to-give-it-a-try/</guid><description>Microsoft has released betas of its various Visual Studio 11 editions – Ultimate, Premium, Professional, Test Professional and Express – along with Team Foundation Server and the .NET Framework 4.5.
And of course it’s no coincidence that the latest version of the IDE has arrived on the same day as the Windows 8 Consumer Preview. Visual Studio is all about developing for Windows 8, and its integrated tools for publishing directly to the new Windows App Store will make it much easier for developers to reach a potentially huge market.</description><content>&lt;p>Microsoft has released betas of its various Visual Studio 11 editions – Ultimate, Premium, Professional, Test Professional and Express – along with Team Foundation Server and the .NET Framework 4.5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course it’s no coincidence that the latest version of the IDE has arrived on the same day as the Windows 8 Consumer Preview. Visual Studio is all about developing for Windows 8, and its integrated tools for publishing directly to the new Windows App Store will make it much easier for developers to reach a potentially huge market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The change you’ll notice first is what Microsoft call Visual Studio’s “minimalist” interface. Colour has been largely stripped out, toolbars removed or refined in an attempt to reduce distractions within the IDE and free up more workspace for browsing your code. Meanwhile you can now browse code directly from the Solution Explorer, helping to further reduce on-screen clutter as you’re less likely to need to open additional windows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Productivity improvements include the ability to pin frequently used files to the left side of the tab well for easier access. You can now preview files directly from the code editor; the new Quick Launch feature helps you locate commands, open Options dialog boxes or switch between open documents; and there’s enhanced support for multi-monitor setups (you can now float multiple windows together from one monitor to another, and bring them back with a key press, for instance).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And elsewhere you’ll find a stack of code editor improvements, new language features, simplified debugging, new 2 and 3D graphics development tools, and the list goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’d like to sample all this for yourself then the simplest solution is download the high-end Ultimate Edition ISO file. And the good news is that you can install and run this alongside Visual Studio 2010. Although whether you want to do that is open to question, as the setup process will carry out an in-place upgrade from .NET 4 to .NET 4.5. Microsoft claim it “provides very high app compatibility for all .NET 4 scenarios”, but that doesn’t mean you won’t have problems, although you can at least uninstall it if things go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re looking for one of the other editions, though, Premium, Professional and Test Professional are available from the &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/downloads#vs">Microsoft site&lt;/a>, along with &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/downloads#groups">Team Foundation Server&lt;/a>, various &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/downloads#groups">Visual Studio Express&lt;/a> editions and &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/downloads#groups">assorted standalone installers&lt;/a>: .NET 4.5, the Visual Studio SDK and so on).&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Matchem Poker: A Great Poker Game For Your Windows Phone</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-01-04-matchem-poker-a-great-poker-game-for-your-windows-phone-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 22:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-01-04-matchem-poker-a-great-poker-game-for-your-windows-phone-2/</guid><description>I am pleased to announce that my game is called “Match`em Poker”. It is a poker game for Windows Phone 7.5 Codename: Mango and it is now available for free on Windows Phone Market Place. I hope to share a lot of my exciting developing experience on this blog.
On top of being a fully functional, free poker game, I’ve also made sure to address key complaints That I heard from people regarding the previous poker and cards game on market place: the main function of the game, that is general touch responsiveness than any other game present on Market Place.</description><content>&lt;p>I am pleased to announce that my game is called “&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Match`em Poker&lt;/a>”. It is a poker game for Windows Phone 7.5 Codename: Mango and it is now available for free on Windows Phone Market Place. I hope to share a lot of my exciting developing experience on this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of being a fully functional, free poker game, I’ve also made sure to address key complaints That I heard from people regarding the previous poker and cards game on market place: the main function of the game, that is general touch responsiveness than any other game present on Market Place.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image002.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>****&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“Match`em Poker”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, my Game is called &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Matchem Poker&lt;/a>. Instead of focusing on just raw performance from a development&lt;/p>
&lt;p>standpoint, I wanted to show how I would envision a great Windows Phone Game. I believe that for a v1.0. release, I have delivered a great initial app experience. I decided to try and demonstrate a happy compromise, hoping to yield a wonderful experience that doesn’t take short-cuts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Touch Responsive&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Great Performance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Improved Gestures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· A Beautiful Experience, yet differentiated enough&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· A emphasis on Design&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(The name? It’s a little odd yet creative. The intersection of poker (Matchem) and the fun of the game This means to match the poker hands).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An emphasis on design and rich Visuals The design system for Windows Phone, code-named “Metro”, really is cool. Others have written about the experience before, but it really is a very developer-friendly design system that is crisp, clean, and once you understand the core principles and rules, it’s easy to build jaw-dropping apps. I’m just a geek, but feel I’ve come away with a pretty good first release when it comes to visual consistency and trying to adhere to the basics of “Metro”. This comes through in a few ways. If you look to the screenshots below, on the left, you see the nice visuals in the “Start” listing: no rounded corners, crisp and clean, etc. On the right, the “info” item for a page shows a few large, rich photos from the venue – and clicking them brings up the fullscreen experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image004.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>                                             &lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image006.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A fun experience&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Playing the Game the feature you get is that on every level you will get general information on Poker which is quite good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>An update with specials is coming soon&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that the app is out there, an update coming soon will add specials support, and I’ll also work to address any large buckets of customer-reported bugs. Thanks to getting the build out earlier in the week for people with developer unlocked phones, I’ve been able to start identifying a few small bugs and issues that I hope to correct soon (thanks everyone).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>From a Blank Visual Studio Project…. &amp;lt;90 Days&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I have created a visual studio project few months before purchasing my windows phone I have completed building and coding my game the thing which last is to test on actual windows phone 7 device the advantage of this is that you will not need to worry about any objection from Windows Phone Marketplace team you can review your and fix all the bugs you found during debugging on a device although, you can run it on emulator but many features would not work on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally I got my windows phone (HTC HD 7) and I am very happy after that I registered a domain &lt;a href="http://www.shayananique.com">shayananique.com&lt;/a> and added everything about my game on my blog I have also previously mentioned about my Invasion (game for windows phone) on my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development happened in spurts as I found a free Sunday afternoon or a clear night or two. I’m Really glad that I was able to the have the opportunity to build a feature-complete WP app and that Microsoft is open to this kind of project as appropriate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, check out the site and &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">download&lt;/a> the app from marketplace if you’re into Windows Phone&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>