<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Metro on Shayan Anique</title><link>https://shayananique.com/categories/metro/</link><description>Recent content in Metro on Shayan Anique</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 01:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shayananique.com/categories/metro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lets start Windows 8 Development</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-09-09-lets-start-windows-8-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-09-09-lets-start-windows-8-development/</guid><description>So, I am digging in to Windows 8 Development since the last //BUILD Conference, Yup! That’s true I am hacking around Windows 8 story since the first Developer Preview version come out, Now I am running Windows 8 Pro (RTM) on my All machines because I am in love with it. Currently, I am porting my Matchem Poker game and Sound Recorder application for Windows Phone to Windows 8. I am using a smart program called “MonoGame”.</description><content>&lt;p>So, I am digging in to Windows 8 Development since the last //BUILD Conference, Yup! That’s true I am hacking around Windows 8 story since the first Developer Preview version come out, Now I am running Windows 8 Pro (RTM) on my All machines because I am in love with it. Currently, I am porting my &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Matchem Poker&lt;/a> game and &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/6dbd2538-0df6-4231-8ae9-62ea18108c8c">Sound Recorder&lt;/a> application for Windows Phone to Windows 8. I am using a smart program called “MonoGame”. It is a program which you can use to port your XNA Windows Phone Game to Windows 8 &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Metro&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will post my full porting story to my Blog Soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Basics&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8devgear">&lt;strong>Download Windows 8 RTM and Visual Studio 2012&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – in this scenario, you will download an install Windows 8 on your machine (or a VM), and run it as your operating system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/32Launch">30 To Launch&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> – Your App.  Your Idea.  In 30 Days.  Microsoft has set up an amazing program for aspiring app developers to not only keep their app motivation going, but also to help you make your app &lt;strong>awesome&lt;/strong>.  Design consultations, tech reviews, and expert help in Microsoft App Excellence Labs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Resources to Learn From&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8samples">&lt;strong>Windows 8 Code Samples&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – a huge array of Windows 8 sample code for almost everything you can think to do in a Win8 app.  Most of the samples include code using C#, Javascript, C++, or Visual Basic.  &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8sampledownload">You can also download the entire set here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/win8RCdevcamp">&lt;strong>Windows 8 Dev Camp in a Box&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – a huge pile of presentations, sample code, and hands-on labs for you to use as you start learning about Windows 8 development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cool Stuff to Checkout&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="span-stylefont-size-smallwindows-8-productivity-who-moved-my-cheese-oh-there-it-isspanhttpwwwhanselmancomblogwindows8productivitywhomovedmycheeseohthereitisaspx">&lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/Windows8ProductivityWhoMovedMyCheeseOhThereItIs.aspx">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Windows 8 productivity: Who moved my cheese? Oh, there it is.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylefont-size-smalla-hrefhttpcompositecodecom20120816html-css-javascript-and-metro-app-building-on-windows-8-part-1html-css-javascript-and-metro-app-building-on-windows-8-part-1aspan">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Metro App Building on Windows 8 Part 1&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Getting Started with Windows 8 Development?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Office 2013 Consumer Preview Released, Metro, Metro, Metro, Everywhere</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-07-18-office-2013-consumer-preview-released-metro-metro-metro-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-07-18-office-2013-consumer-preview-released-metro-metro-metro-everywhere/</guid><description>As I mentioned on my tweet earlier Microsoft Released Consumer Preview of their new and Shiny Office 2013.
As we all are office geek we use it on daily basis for documents, spreadsheets, presentation and so on.
This year Microsoft done something different revising their own UI they added Metro in it like Windows 8 since there as no specific download and licenses for Microsoft Office 2013 you can download the beta version which is in modern world called as Consumer Previews to test what Microsoft is actually doing with their products.</description><content>&lt;p>As I mentioned on my tweet earlier Microsoft Released Consumer Preview of their new and Shiny &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/office/preview/">Office 2013&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>As we all are office geek we use it on daily basis for documents, spreadsheets, presentation and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/office2013icons.png">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year Microsoft done something different revising their own UI they added Metro in it like Windows 8 since there as no specific download and licenses for Microsoft Office 2013 you can download the beta version which is in modern world called as Consumer Previews to test what Microsoft is actually doing with their products. One thing Skydrive is fully integrated with Office 2013 like Windows 8 which is a good thing because if any disaster happens with us our important documents and files will be save and when it rains we can see it&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> I am kidding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps the biggest change to Office 2013 isn’t the way it looks or its features, but rather the way documents are delivered along with some important under-the-hood changes. Microsoft is really pushing the ability to create a Word document on a Windows PC and edit it on a Windows Phone, Windows 8 tablet, or any Windows 7- or Windows 8-based PC with an internet connection. Home users can store documents in Microsoft’s SkyDrive cloud storage and businesses can use a range of the company’s SharePoint offerings. Office 2013’s big innovation is its ability to let users stream a full-featured version of Office to a PC with personal settings intact — an on-demand Office suite whenever you require it. This is a big step from previous versions of Office that included cloud-based storage options, but never really tied them together into one neat package.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Office on demand is a powerful aspect to Microsoft’s Office 2013 subscription offering, providing a way to access a full version of Office wherever you are. The service lets you stream a full-featured Office application to any internet-connected PC running Windows 7 and Windows 8, providing access to the settings and documents you use regularly. Simply put, you can sign in to a streaming version of Office at a friend’s PC and finish a document; the app will then be removed from the PC once it’s closed. This all requires an Office 365 Home Premium subscription, but its ease-of-use makes it a compelling prospect for users who are comfortable using Microsoft’s Office suite and require more document editing functionality than Google Docs or Microsoft’s own Office Web Apps provide. Despite this, you can still opt to simply buy a standalone version of the Office 2013 desktop software and utilize SkyDrive as an online storage hub for documents. You won’t get the streaming Office 2013 apps, but you’ll benefit from the cloud and avoid having to pay a subscription fee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/office/preview/">So Keep enjoy the preview of Microsoft Office 2013.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Windows Phone 8 Announced</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-06-20-windows-phone-8-announced-big-roll-up-in-the-tech-industry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-06-20-windows-phone-8-announced-big-roll-up-in-the-tech-industry/</guid><description>Today at Windows Phone Summit Microsoft announced there upcoming version of Windows Phone known as Windows Phone 8 Codename “Apollo”. This OS will be successor to previous Windows Phone 7 series as it contains biggest improvements that everybody wanted. The Windows Phone 8 announcement was aimed largely at Microsoft’s ecosystem of developers and hardware partners, and somewhat at potential enterprise customers, more so than at smartphone consumers. While the company’s executives revealed several end-user and consumer features–like the Wallet Hub, a new Start screen, upgraded hardware support (including support for NFC)–the major news revolved around the operating system’s revamped kernel, which it now shares as common code with Windows 8.</description><content>&lt;p>Today at Windows Phone Summit Microsoft announced there upcoming version of Windows Phone known as Windows Phone 8 Codename “Apollo”. This OS will be successor to previous Windows Phone 7 series as it contains biggest improvements that everybody wanted. The Windows Phone 8 announcement was aimed largely at Microsoft’s ecosystem of developers and hardware partners, and somewhat at potential enterprise customers, more so than at smartphone consumers. While the company’s executives revealed several end-user and consumer features–like the Wallet Hub, a new Start screen, upgraded hardware support (including support for NFC)–the major news revolved around the operating system’s revamped kernel, which it now shares as common code with Windows 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They added some new features like SD Card Support, Near Field Communication Sensor “NFC” Developers can make applications and games which depends upon native code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s some shots of Windows Phone 8&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Developers will be able to download Windows Phone 8 SDK at this summer.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>UX Guidelines For Metro App Development</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-05-03-ux-guidelines-for-metro-app-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 11:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-05-03-ux-guidelines-for-metro-app-development/</guid><description>The Windows Developer Preview introduces a new development platform for creating Metro style apps. What is a Metro style app you say?
“Metro style apps are full screen apps tailored to your users’ needs, tailored to the device they run on, tailored for touch interaction, and tailored to the Windows user interface. Windows helps you interact with your users, and your users interact with your app.”
One of my friend asked me where one could find Design Guidelines for Windows 8 Metro apps.</description><content>&lt;p>The Windows Developer Preview introduces a new development platform for creating Metro style apps. What is a Metro style app you say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Metro style apps are full screen apps tailored to your users’ needs, tailored to the device they run on, tailored for touch interaction, and tailored to the Windows user interface. Windows helps you interact with your users, and your users interact with your app.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my friend asked me where one could find Design Guidelines for Windows 8 Metro apps. Bonny Lau, from the Windows team, shared a terrific link to the new &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/apps/">Windows Dev Center&lt;/a>, outlining comprehensive guidelines from planning to building your Metro style app. These guidelines also cover new UI lingo (app bar, charms bar, snap view, etc.), animations, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/semanticzoom-bc1.png">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sources –&amp;gt; &lt;a href="http://blendinsider.com/technical/ux-guidelines-for-metro-style-app-development-2011-10-21/">Blend Insider&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Matchem Poker: A Great Poker Game For Your Windows Phone</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-01-04-matchem-poker-a-great-poker-game-for-your-windows-phone-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 22:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-01-04-matchem-poker-a-great-poker-game-for-your-windows-phone-2/</guid><description>I am pleased to announce that my game is called “Match`em Poker”. It is a poker game for Windows Phone 7.5 Codename: Mango and it is now available for free on Windows Phone Market Place. I hope to share a lot of my exciting developing experience on this blog.
On top of being a fully functional, free poker game, I’ve also made sure to address key complaints That I heard from people regarding the previous poker and cards game on market place: the main function of the game, that is general touch responsiveness than any other game present on Market Place.</description><content>&lt;p>I am pleased to announce that my game is called “&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Match`em Poker&lt;/a>”. It is a poker game for Windows Phone 7.5 Codename: Mango and it is now available for free on Windows Phone Market Place. I hope to share a lot of my exciting developing experience on this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of being a fully functional, free poker game, I’ve also made sure to address key complaints That I heard from people regarding the previous poker and cards game on market place: the main function of the game, that is general touch responsiveness than any other game present on Market Place.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image002.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>****&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“Match`em Poker”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, my Game is called &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Matchem Poker&lt;/a>. Instead of focusing on just raw performance from a development&lt;/p>
&lt;p>standpoint, I wanted to show how I would envision a great Windows Phone Game. I believe that for a v1.0. release, I have delivered a great initial app experience. I decided to try and demonstrate a happy compromise, hoping to yield a wonderful experience that doesn’t take short-cuts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Touch Responsive&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Great Performance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Improved Gestures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· A Beautiful Experience, yet differentiated enough&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· A emphasis on Design&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(The name? It’s a little odd yet creative. The intersection of poker (Matchem) and the fun of the game This means to match the poker hands).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An emphasis on design and rich Visuals The design system for Windows Phone, code-named “Metro”, really is cool. Others have written about the experience before, but it really is a very developer-friendly design system that is crisp, clean, and once you understand the core principles and rules, it’s easy to build jaw-dropping apps. I’m just a geek, but feel I’ve come away with a pretty good first release when it comes to visual consistency and trying to adhere to the basics of “Metro”. This comes through in a few ways. If you look to the screenshots below, on the left, you see the nice visuals in the “Start” listing: no rounded corners, crisp and clean, etc. On the right, the “info” item for a page shows a few large, rich photos from the venue – and clicking them brings up the fullscreen experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image004.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>                                             &lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image006.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A fun experience&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Playing the Game the feature you get is that on every level you will get general information on Poker which is quite good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>An update with specials is coming soon&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that the app is out there, an update coming soon will add specials support, and I’ll also work to address any large buckets of customer-reported bugs. Thanks to getting the build out earlier in the week for people with developer unlocked phones, I’ve been able to start identifying a few small bugs and issues that I hope to correct soon (thanks everyone).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>From a Blank Visual Studio Project…. &amp;lt;90 Days&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I have created a visual studio project few months before purchasing my windows phone I have completed building and coding my game the thing which last is to test on actual windows phone 7 device the advantage of this is that you will not need to worry about any objection from Windows Phone Marketplace team you can review your and fix all the bugs you found during debugging on a device although, you can run it on emulator but many features would not work on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally I got my windows phone (HTC HD 7) and I am very happy after that I registered a domain &lt;a href="http://www.shayananique.com">shayananique.com&lt;/a> and added everything about my game on my blog I have also previously mentioned about my Invasion (game for windows phone) on my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development happened in spurts as I found a free Sunday afternoon or a clear night or two. I’m Really glad that I was able to the have the opportunity to build a feature-complete WP app and that Microsoft is open to this kind of project as appropriate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, check out the site and &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">download&lt;/a> the app from marketplace if you’re into Windows Phone&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>