<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Shayan Anique</title><link>https://shayananique.com/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on Shayan Anique</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:16:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shayananique.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Office 2013 Consumer Preview Released, Metro, Metro, Metro, Everywhere</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-07-18-office-2013-consumer-preview-released-metro-metro-metro-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-07-18-office-2013-consumer-preview-released-metro-metro-metro-everywhere/</guid><description>As I mentioned on my tweet earlier Microsoft Released Consumer Preview of their new and Shiny Office 2013.
As we all are office geek we use it on daily basis for documents, spreadsheets, presentation and so on.
This year Microsoft done something different revising their own UI they added Metro in it like Windows 8 since there as no specific download and licenses for Microsoft Office 2013 you can download the beta version which is in modern world called as Consumer Previews to test what Microsoft is actually doing with their products.</description><content>&lt;p>As I mentioned on my tweet earlier Microsoft Released Consumer Preview of their new and Shiny &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/office/preview/">Office 2013&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>As we all are office geek we use it on daily basis for documents, spreadsheets, presentation and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/office2013icons.png">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year Microsoft done something different revising their own UI they added Metro in it like Windows 8 since there as no specific download and licenses for Microsoft Office 2013 you can download the beta version which is in modern world called as Consumer Previews to test what Microsoft is actually doing with their products. One thing Skydrive is fully integrated with Office 2013 like Windows 8 which is a good thing because if any disaster happens with us our important documents and files will be save and when it rains we can see it&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> I am kidding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps the biggest change to Office 2013 isn’t the way it looks or its features, but rather the way documents are delivered along with some important under-the-hood changes. Microsoft is really pushing the ability to create a Word document on a Windows PC and edit it on a Windows Phone, Windows 8 tablet, or any Windows 7- or Windows 8-based PC with an internet connection. Home users can store documents in Microsoft’s SkyDrive cloud storage and businesses can use a range of the company’s SharePoint offerings. Office 2013’s big innovation is its ability to let users stream a full-featured version of Office to a PC with personal settings intact — an on-demand Office suite whenever you require it. This is a big step from previous versions of Office that included cloud-based storage options, but never really tied them together into one neat package.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Office on demand is a powerful aspect to Microsoft’s Office 2013 subscription offering, providing a way to access a full version of Office wherever you are. The service lets you stream a full-featured Office application to any internet-connected PC running Windows 7 and Windows 8, providing access to the settings and documents you use regularly. Simply put, you can sign in to a streaming version of Office at a friend’s PC and finish a document; the app will then be removed from the PC once it’s closed. This all requires an Office 365 Home Premium subscription, but its ease-of-use makes it a compelling prospect for users who are comfortable using Microsoft’s Office suite and require more document editing functionality than Google Docs or Microsoft’s own Office Web Apps provide. Despite this, you can still opt to simply buy a standalone version of the Office 2013 desktop software and utilize SkyDrive as an online storage hub for documents. You won’t get the streaming Office 2013 apps, but you’ll benefit from the cloud and avoid having to pay a subscription fee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/office/preview/">So Keep enjoy the preview of Microsoft Office 2013.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Windows Phone 8 Announced</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-06-20-windows-phone-8-announced-big-roll-up-in-the-tech-industry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-06-20-windows-phone-8-announced-big-roll-up-in-the-tech-industry/</guid><description>Today at Windows Phone Summit Microsoft announced there upcoming version of Windows Phone known as Windows Phone 8 Codename “Apollo”. This OS will be successor to previous Windows Phone 7 series as it contains biggest improvements that everybody wanted. The Windows Phone 8 announcement was aimed largely at Microsoft’s ecosystem of developers and hardware partners, and somewhat at potential enterprise customers, more so than at smartphone consumers. While the company’s executives revealed several end-user and consumer features–like the Wallet Hub, a new Start screen, upgraded hardware support (including support for NFC)–the major news revolved around the operating system’s revamped kernel, which it now shares as common code with Windows 8.</description><content>&lt;p>Today at Windows Phone Summit Microsoft announced there upcoming version of Windows Phone known as Windows Phone 8 Codename “Apollo”. This OS will be successor to previous Windows Phone 7 series as it contains biggest improvements that everybody wanted. The Windows Phone 8 announcement was aimed largely at Microsoft’s ecosystem of developers and hardware partners, and somewhat at potential enterprise customers, more so than at smartphone consumers. While the company’s executives revealed several end-user and consumer features–like the Wallet Hub, a new Start screen, upgraded hardware support (including support for NFC)–the major news revolved around the operating system’s revamped kernel, which it now shares as common code with Windows 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They added some new features like SD Card Support, Near Field Communication Sensor “NFC” Developers can make applications and games which depends upon native code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s some shots of Windows Phone 8&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Developers will be able to download Windows Phone 8 SDK at this summer.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>UX Guidelines For Metro App Development</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-05-03-ux-guidelines-for-metro-app-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 11:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-05-03-ux-guidelines-for-metro-app-development/</guid><description>The Windows Developer Preview introduces a new development platform for creating Metro style apps. What is a Metro style app you say?
“Metro style apps are full screen apps tailored to your users’ needs, tailored to the device they run on, tailored for touch interaction, and tailored to the Windows user interface. Windows helps you interact with your users, and your users interact with your app.”
One of my friend asked me where one could find Design Guidelines for Windows 8 Metro apps.</description><content>&lt;p>The Windows Developer Preview introduces a new development platform for creating Metro style apps. What is a Metro style app you say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Metro style apps are full screen apps tailored to your users’ needs, tailored to the device they run on, tailored for touch interaction, and tailored to the Windows user interface. Windows helps you interact with your users, and your users interact with your app.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my friend asked me where one could find Design Guidelines for Windows 8 Metro apps. Bonny Lau, from the Windows team, shared a terrific link to the new &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/apps/">Windows Dev Center&lt;/a>, outlining comprehensive guidelines from planning to building your Metro style app. These guidelines also cover new UI lingo (app bar, charms bar, snap view, etc.), animations, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/semanticzoom-bc1.png">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sources –&amp;gt; &lt;a href="http://blendinsider.com/technical/ux-guidelines-for-metro-style-app-development-2011-10-21/">Blend Insider&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The problem with metro is it’s hard to differentiate</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-04-05-the-problem-with-metro-is-its-hard-to-differentiate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 16:58:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-04-05-the-problem-with-metro-is-its-hard-to-differentiate/</guid><description>want you all to pause a moment or two.
I want you all to sit in front of Windows 8, and explore it some more and get to be intimate with “metro” as a user interface style. Really, immerse yourself in it and just stare at it, explore every pixel it offers up.
I now want you to imagine that this is going to be your user interface for the next 5 years.</description><content>&lt;p>want you all to pause a moment or two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want you all to sit in front of Windows 8, and explore it some more and get to be intimate with “metro” as a user interface style. Really, immerse yourself in it and just stare at it, explore every pixel it offers up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I now want you to imagine that this is going to be your user interface for the next 5 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Still onboard?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>I have been doing “metro” rinse/repeat designs for quite some time and it has long past bored me to the point where I wonder if I have metro-blindness now. That is I’ve stared at it for far to long that I really need a release valve, I crave something more interesting and has more depth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the part where you respond with the usual metro rhetoric about content-first design, authentically digital blah blah the usual Microsoft Metro Zombie response that often the person at the other end of the conversation has no clue at what even it means, it just sounds smart to say and gives one a sense of authority over the conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not saying the path that Microsoft has put the hordes of developers on is wrong but I’m not inclined to say it’s right either.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="span-stylefont-weight-boldwho-is-the-target-audiencespan">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Who is the target audience?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Today, a 50 something non-techy came into my work pod to talk about the new iPad 3, we talked about what it has and doesn’t have but then I tried to get an unbiased non-technical opinion on Windows 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Me: “Have you seen the new Windows 8 yet?”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>NonTechGuy: “Nope.. is it out?”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Me: “Not yet, it’s still in beta, but here have a look”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I then watched his facial expression; it looked like he wanted to go to the toilet but was holding back on saying so out of politeness.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Me: “Cool huh!”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>NonTechGuy: “is that the whole thing?”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Bottom line was that he was not excited by it and we soon retreated to the iPad conversation. My thinking here is not that well this user speaks for billions of humans worldwide; it was just interesting to see a virgin reaction to basically metro.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This person uses Windows daily and has no issue with it, but when shown Windows 8 front-start screen it had this jarring effect on his senses, as if to say – “&lt;em>this is not what I expected&lt;/em>”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the part where someone now responds with “&lt;em>give them time&lt;/em>”, “&lt;em>users over time will get used to it&lt;/em>”, “&lt;em>I have xyz friends who see the opposite to this view&lt;/em>” etc. etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I get it, I just disagree with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Windows 8 is targeted at us, the tech crowd, the more I think about its practicality the more I contemplate that maybe the reason why Apple is much more successful than Microsoft at this space as they target the baby-boomer style crowd. Microsoft and Google target us and in turn they fail more than they succeed simply because we are much harder to please than the Apple audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When Steve Jobs said that they only make products that they would want to use, I think we all in the tech-scene assumed he meant us. He didn’t, I think he meant to say “no, I mean guys my age and people who aren’t preoccupied with engadget/gizmodo style blogs.. I mean me, you people aren’t invited”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing that struck a chord today was the fact that iPad3 has failed in the eyes of most tech bloggers etc., yet 50-something non-tech guy walks into the IT cubicle and asks “Hey, you seen the new iPad!”..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about that a bit more. Firstly, he has already heard about it from mainstream radio stations and secondly he did not say iPad3 he said “new iPad” (interesting choice of words to parrot).&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Matchem Poker: A Great Poker Game For Your Windows Phone</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-01-04-matchem-poker-a-great-poker-game-for-your-windows-phone-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 22:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2012-01-04-matchem-poker-a-great-poker-game-for-your-windows-phone-2/</guid><description>I am pleased to announce that my game is called “Match`em Poker”. It is a poker game for Windows Phone 7.5 Codename: Mango and it is now available for free on Windows Phone Market Place. I hope to share a lot of my exciting developing experience on this blog.
On top of being a fully functional, free poker game, I’ve also made sure to address key complaints That I heard from people regarding the previous poker and cards game on market place: the main function of the game, that is general touch responsiveness than any other game present on Market Place.</description><content>&lt;p>I am pleased to announce that my game is called “&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Match`em Poker&lt;/a>”. It is a poker game for Windows Phone 7.5 Codename: Mango and it is now available for free on Windows Phone Market Place. I hope to share a lot of my exciting developing experience on this blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of being a fully functional, free poker game, I’ve also made sure to address key complaints That I heard from people regarding the previous poker and cards game on market place: the main function of the game, that is general touch responsiveness than any other game present on Market Place.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image002.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>****&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>“Match`em Poker”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, my Game is called &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">Matchem Poker&lt;/a>. Instead of focusing on just raw performance from a development&lt;/p>
&lt;p>standpoint, I wanted to show how I would envision a great Windows Phone Game. I believe that for a v1.0. release, I have delivered a great initial app experience. I decided to try and demonstrate a happy compromise, hoping to yield a wonderful experience that doesn’t take short-cuts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Touch Responsive&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Great Performance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· Improved Gestures&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· A Beautiful Experience, yet differentiated enough&lt;/p>
&lt;p>· A emphasis on Design&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(The name? It’s a little odd yet creative. The intersection of poker (Matchem) and the fun of the game This means to match the poker hands).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An emphasis on design and rich Visuals The design system for Windows Phone, code-named “Metro”, really is cool. Others have written about the experience before, but it really is a very developer-friendly design system that is crisp, clean, and once you understand the core principles and rules, it’s easy to build jaw-dropping apps. I’m just a geek, but feel I’ve come away with a pretty good first release when it comes to visual consistency and trying to adhere to the basics of “Metro”. This comes through in a few ways. If you look to the screenshots below, on the left, you see the nice visuals in the “Start” listing: no rounded corners, crisp and clean, etc. On the right, the “info” item for a page shows a few large, rich photos from the venue – and clicking them brings up the fullscreen experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image004.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>                                             &lt;a href="http://shayananique.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/clip_image006.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A fun experience&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Playing the Game the feature you get is that on every level you will get general information on Poker which is quite good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>An update with specials is coming soon&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that the app is out there, an update coming soon will add specials support, and I’ll also work to address any large buckets of customer-reported bugs. Thanks to getting the build out earlier in the week for people with developer unlocked phones, I’ve been able to start identifying a few small bugs and issues that I hope to correct soon (thanks everyone).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>From a Blank Visual Studio Project…. &amp;lt;90 Days&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I have created a visual studio project few months before purchasing my windows phone I have completed building and coding my game the thing which last is to test on actual windows phone 7 device the advantage of this is that you will not need to worry about any objection from Windows Phone Marketplace team you can review your and fix all the bugs you found during debugging on a device although, you can run it on emulator but many features would not work on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally I got my windows phone (HTC HD 7) and I am very happy after that I registered a domain &lt;a href="http://www.shayananique.com">shayananique.com&lt;/a> and added everything about my game on my blog I have also previously mentioned about my Invasion (game for windows phone) on my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most development happened in spurts as I found a free Sunday afternoon or a clear night or two. I’m Really glad that I was able to the have the opportunity to build a feature-complete WP app and that Microsoft is open to this kind of project as appropriate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, check out the site and &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-GB/apps/081f188d-fe71-4015-b568-b4f1186bf039">download&lt;/a> the app from marketplace if you’re into Windows Phone&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>The Importance of Excel in the Work Place</title><link>https://shayananique.com/posts/2011-10-20-the-importance-of-excel-in-the-work-place/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shayananique.com/posts/2011-10-20-the-importance-of-excel-in-the-work-place/</guid><description>Excel is perhaps the most important computer software program used in the workplace today. That’s why so many workers and prospective employees are required to learn Excel in order to enter or remain in the workplace.
From the viewpoint of the employer, particularly those in the field of information systems, the use of Excel as an end-user computing tool is essential. Not only are many business professionals using Excel to perform everyday functional tasks in the workplace, an increasing number of employers rely on Excel for decision support.</description><content>&lt;p>Excel is perhaps the most important computer software program used in the workplace today. That’s why so many workers and prospective employees are required to learn Excel in order to enter or remain in the workplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the viewpoint of the employer, particularly those in the field of information systems, the use of Excel as an end-user computing tool is essential. Not only are many business professionals using Excel to perform everyday functional tasks in the workplace, an increasing number of employers rely on Excel for decision support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In general, Excel dominates the spreadsheet product industry with a market share estimated at 90 percent. Excel 2007 has the capacity for spreadsheets of up to a million rows by 16,000 columns, enabling the user to import and work with massive amounts of data and achieve faster calculation performance than ever before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Outside the workplace, Excel is in broad use for everyday problem solving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s say you have a home office. You can use Excel to calculate sales tax on a purchase, calculate the cost of a trip by car, create a temperature converter, calculate the price of pizza per square inch and do analysis of inputted data. You can track your debt, income and assets, determine your debt to income ratio, calculate your net worth, and use this information to prepare for the process of applying for a mortgage on a new house. The personal uses for Excel are almost as endless as the business uses for this software – and an Excel tutorial delves into the practical uses of the program for personal and business use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The use of spreadsheets on computers is not new. Spreadsheets, in electronic form, have been in existence since before the introduction of the personal computer. Forerunners to Excel and Lotus 1-2-3 were packages such as VisiCalc, developed and modeled on the accountant’s financial ledger. Since 1987, spreadsheet programs have been impacting the business world. Along the way, computerized spreadsheets have become a pervasive and increasingly effective tool for comparative data analysis throughout the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, end users employ Excel to create and modify spreadsheets as well as to author web pages with links and complex formatting specifications. They create macros and scripts. While some of these programs are small, one-shot calculations, many are much more critical and affect significant financial decisions and business transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Widely used by businesses, service agencies, volunteer groups, private sector organizations, scientists, students, educators, trainers, researchers, journalists, accountants and others, Microsoft Excel has become a staple of end users and business professionals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beauty of Excel is that it can be used as a receiver of workplace or business data, or as a calculator, a decision support tool, a data converter or even a display spreadsheet for information interpretation. Excel can create a chart or graph, operate in conjunction with Mail Merge functions, import data from the Internet, create a concept map and sequentially rank information by importance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excel offers new data analysis and visualization tools that assist in analyzing information, spotting trends and accessing information more easily than in the past. Using conditional formatting with rich data display schemes, you can evaluate and illustrate important trends and highlight exceptions with colored gradients, data bars and icons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, Excel can be customized to perform such a wide variety of functions that many businesses can’t operate without it. Excel training has become mandatory in many workplaces; in fact, computer software training is a must for any workplace trying to keep up with the times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s say you’re an employer with 97 workers, 17 of whom called in sick today, and you want to know the percentage represented by absentees. Excel can do that. You can learn Excel and use it to determine the ratio of male to female employees, the percentage of minorities on the payroll, and the ranking of each worker by compensation package amount, including the percentages of that package according to pay and benefits. You can use Excel to keep track of production by department, information that may assist you in future development plans. You can create additional spreadsheets to track data on vendors and customers while maintaining an ongoing inventory of product stock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s say you want to know your business production versus cost. You don’t have to be a math wiz – you just have to learn Excel. Excel allows you to input all of the data, analyze it, sort it according to your customized format, and display the results with color, shading, backgrounds, icons and other gimmicks that offer time-saving assistance in later locating precisely the information desired. If this spreadsheet is for presentation purposes, Excel helps you put it together in such a visually appealing way that the data may seem to pop and sparkle.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>